Raymond J. Norris

11482 Lowell Ave, Overland Park KS 66210 ray@rayjnorris.com (913) 522-3611

Summary

Senior Software Development Manager with 25+ years experience leading large scale software automation projects using Agile practices.

Accomplishments

Acumen in Mortgage Lending Automation across the Origination Channel with considerable focus in Automated Underwriting, Lead Management processes and support systems.

Led the development of Residential Mortgage Automated Underwriting systems for three companies.

Teach and practice Lean Agile project management methodologies with strong customer focus and participation.

Current Concentrations

Software Automation Project Management and Leadership using Agile methodologies.

Website Development using Laravel Full Stack.

Financial Business Systems.

Experience

RayJNorris.com Consultancy 2009-Present

- * Turner House Children's Clinic, 2011-17
- * HappyValleyFidders.org, 2015-17
- * SOSRide.org, 2015-17
- * CapitusGroup.com, 2013-14
- * MetropolitanReporters.com, 2010
- * TheWayWomenWork.com, 2009
- * InnovaPrep.com, 2010-17

Stonegate Mortgage Corp, Project Manager/ Business Analyst 2014-15

Led development of an internet based Non-Agency Eligibility system for Stonegate's origination channel(s). The system provides sub-second multi-investor guideline evaluation and approval returns.

Salva O'Renick, Director of Digital Interactive 2008

Introduced Digital Marketing skills, strategy, and operations into the organization. Implemented Agile development and project management; implemented CRM based opportunity and sales management using Salesforce.com.

First Horizon Home Loans, Inc., Project Manager/ Business Analyst 2005-6

Created and staffed the Information Technology organization at First Horizon Home Loans; delivered FAMUS, First Horizon's first web-based Loan Origination system.

Novastar Financial, Inc. SVP Information Systems, 1997 – 2004

Created and staffed the Information Technology organization at Novastar Financial Inc.; delivered fourteen business systems, most notably the first web-based Subprime Loan Origination systems; opened six large offices, instrumental in growing the business from startup to a multi-billion dollar business.

Saxon Mortgage, Inc., SVP Information Systems, 1991 – 1996

Created and staffed the Information Technology organization at Saxon Mortgage, Inc.; delivered SOLO (Saxon Online Loan Origination) system, instrumental in growing the business from startup.

Education

Business Information Systems Degree, 3.91 GPA 1985

United States Air Force, Radio Relay, Secret Security Clearance 1973 - 1975